A Finding Aid to the W.G. Constable Papers, 1905-1983, bulk 1920-1976, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Lectures, 1909-1963; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 4.6 Linear feet Box 8-12
  - Lecture Tour, Canada, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Lecture Tour, Northern Europe, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Lecture Tour, Scandinavia, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Lecture Trip, Poland, 1957, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - "13th and 14th Century French and English Illuminated Manuscripts", Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - "18th Century Art Themes with Special Reference to Landscapes", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - "18th Century Painting, France" (Lecture 1), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - "18th Century Painting, France" (Lecture 2), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - "18th Century Painting, France" (from 2 lectures), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - "18th Century English Painting", circa 1930-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - "18th Century English Painting", circa 1930-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - "18th Century English Painting", circa 1930-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - "18th Century English Painting, Watercolors, Later Portraits", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - "18th Century English Portrait Painters", 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - "19th Century French Painting" (Lecture 1), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - "19th Century French Painting" (Lecture 2), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - "19th Century Painting, Landscapes in England", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - "Art and Academic Study," University of Western Ontario, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - "Art and Democracy," The Club, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - "Art and Everyday Life", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - "Art and Geographical Influences," Oxford, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - "Art and Social Welfare", 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - "Art Galleries and Museums in Soviet Russia", 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - "Art Galleries and Social Welfare," Leicester, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - "Art History and Academic Study", 1948, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Art History as a Subject of Academic Study", 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Art in the Service of Religion," Duke University, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Art, Its Place in a Changing World", 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Art Museums in the U.S." (radio program), 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Art Schools and Community", 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Artistic Relations of England and Italy, Middle Ages, Tudor", 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Artistic Relations of England and Italy, 17th Century" (Lecture I and II), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Artistic Relations of England and Italy, 17th Century" (Lecture III), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "Artistic Relations of England and Italy, 17th Century" (Lecture IV), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Artistic Relations of England and Italy, 17th Century", 1952, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Arts in a Changing World," Ohio State, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Arts in Boston", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Arts in Education", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "Arts in the USA", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Importance of Art in Life and Function of Art School", 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "Canaletto", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - "Care of Paintings," Boston School of Architecture, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "Collecting for a Museum", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - "Collecting in the U.S." (Lecture I), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - "Collecting in the U.S." (Lecture II), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - "Collecting with Karolik", 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - "Collectors and Collecting" (early version), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - "Collectors and Collecting", 1958, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Commencement Speech, Rhode Island School of Design, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - "Conservation and Reconstruction in Poland", 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - "Curator as Collector", circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - "Education in the Arts as an Element in the Integration of Human Culture", 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - "El Greco and Velazquez", 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - "English Art, 19th and 20th Century, Constable to Bacon", 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "English Conversation Pieces", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - "English Dilettanti and Art Collectors", 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - "English Landscape in Poetry and Painting", circa 1950-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - "English Medieval Painting", 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - "English Medieval Painting, 7th Century - 1250" (Lecture I), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - "English Medieval Painting, 1250-1350" (Lecture II), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - "English Medieval Painting, 1350-1480" (Lecture III), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - "English Medieval Painting, 1480-1600" (Lecture IV), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - "English Painting and English Life, 1700-1850", 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - "English Painting, 1900-1950", 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - "English Patrons and Italian Painters" (Lecture I), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - "English Patrons and Italian Painters" (Lecture II), circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "English Watercolors", 1945, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Ethics for Museum Men," Fogg Art Museum, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "European Museums and Impressions of Europe", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Examination of Pictures", 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "French Painting, 1400-1900", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "German Problem", 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Goya", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Growth of the British Labour Party", 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Humanism and Art", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Impressionism and Post-Impressionism", 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Influence of Constable and Turner on Landscape Painting in Europe", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "Influence of Italy on 17th and 18th Century English Architecture", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "International Cooperation and Conservation", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Italian Art in Time of Dante" (Lecture I), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "Italian Art in Time of Dante" (Lecture II), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Italian Art in Time of Dante" (Lecture III), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Italian Art in Time of Dante" (Lecture IV), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "Italian Art in Time of Dante" (Lecture V), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Italian Art in Time of Dante" (Lecture VI), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - "Italian Baroque Painting", 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - "Italian Landscape Painting" (Lecture I), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - "Italian Landscape Painting" (Lecture II), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "Italian Landscape Painting, 18th Century" (Lecture III), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - "Italian Landscape Painting, 18th Century" (Lecture IV), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - "Italian Landscape Painting, 18th Century Influence on English Painting" (Lecture V), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "Italian Painting, 13th Century", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - "Italian Painting, 13th Century and 14th Century", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "Italian Painting, 18th Century", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - "Italian Painting, 18th Century", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "Italian Painting, Fra Angelico, Fra Lippi, Botticelli", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "Italian Painting, High Renaissance, Da Vinci", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - "Italian Painting, High Renaissance, Michaelangelo", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - "Italian Painting, High Renaissance, Raphael", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "Italian Painting, High Renaissance, Giorgione and Titian", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "Italian Painting, Mantegna, Bellini, and Tura", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Italian Painting, Piero Della Francesca and Signorelli", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Italian Painting, Tintoretto and Veronese", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Italian Painting, Uccello, Veneziano, del Castagno", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "John Constable", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "Joseph M.W. Turner", 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "Karl Baedeker", 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Landscapes, East and West", 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - "Lowell Institute Lectures" (I), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - "Lowell Institute Lectures" (II), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Lowell Institute Lectures" (III), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - "Lowell Institute Lectures" (IV), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "Lowell Institute Lectures" (V), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "Lowell Institute Lectures" (VI), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - "Lowell Institute Lectures" (VII), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - "Lowell Institute Lectures" (VIII), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "Luxury and the Economic State", 1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "Mantegna and Humanism in Fifteenth Century Italy", 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "Masterpieces of 18th Century Painting and Sculpture", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - "Medieval Painting, Introduciton, Romanesque" (Lecture I), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - "Medieval Painting, England" (Lecture II), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - "Medieval Painting, France" (Lecture III), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - "Medieval Painting, Early Flemish" (Lecture IV), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - "Medieval Painting, Netherlands, 15th Century" (Lecture V), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - "Medieval Paintings" (Lecture VI), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - "Morality and Art," Smith, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - "Mural Painting in England, 17th and 18th Century" (Lecture I), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - "Mural Painting in England, 17th and 18th Century" (Lecture II), circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - "Museum Acquisitions," Fogg Art Museum, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - "Museum Problems", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - "Museums and Contemporary Art", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - "Museums of the Future," Fogg Art Museum, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - "National Gallery of Canada and Its Work", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - "New Art and Old Morals," Institute of Religion and Social Studies, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - "Old Master Drawings," Bristol University, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - "Painter's Workshop", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - "Painting in 18th Century America", 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Painting in 19th Century Europe" (Lecture I), 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - "Painting in 19th Century Europe" (Lecture II), 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "Painting in 19th Century Europe" (Lecture III), 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "Painting in 19th Century Europe" (Lecture IV), 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - "Painting in 19th Century Europe" (Lecture V), 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - "Painting in 19th Century Europe" (Lecture VI), 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - "Place of Art in Education", 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - "Place of Art in Social Life", circa 1920-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "Pre-Raphaelites", 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - "Present Position of German Museums", 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - "Problems and Possessions of American Art Galleries", 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - "Relations of American and British 18th Century Art", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - "Review of Friedlander's David to Delacroix", 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - "Richard Wilson", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - "Rubens, up to 1630", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - "Rubens, 1630-1940; Van Dyke", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "Sienese and Gothic Influence in Florence and Northern Italy", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - "Sienese Painting, 14th and 15th Centuries", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - "Social Necessity of Art", 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - "Some Masterpieces of the Boston Museum", 1942, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - "Sometimes a Miracle Happens", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - "Spanish 17th Century Painting", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - "Spanish Painting", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - "Spiritual Problems of an Artist", 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - "Sport and Art", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - "Still Life Painting Since 1470," Cincinnati Art Museum, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - "Typographical Tradition in 18th Century Italy," Athenaeum, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - "Twenty Years of Study in Renaissance History of Art", 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - "Two Canalettos", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - "Velasquez and 17th Century Spanish Painting", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - "Velasquez and the School of Madrid", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - "Venetian 18th Century Painting", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - "Venetian Painters in England in the 18th Century", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - "Venice and England in the 18th Century", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - "Visitor to Venice", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - "Visual Arts as an Aspect of the Human Spirit," Columbia University, 1953, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - "Visual Arts", 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - "Where Do We Go From Here? Or Museum Problems in a Changing World", 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - "Whistler," Nottingham University, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - "Why Waste Money on Art Galleries?", 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - "William Hogarth", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - "William Morris", circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - "Works of Art in Wartime", 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 44)
- Writings and Notes, 1910-1974; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Box 13-14
  Writings consist of Constable's published articles on art, exhibition catalog introductions, and articles submitted for the Encyclopedia of World Art. Essay drafts include writings and translations from Constable's early university years, in addition to later essays that touch on concerns of museum curatorship. The series also includes miscellaneous writing notes, bibliographies, and drafts and research material related to Art Collecting in the United States, Art History and Connoisseurship, and The Painter's Workshop.
  Materials are arranged by document type and retain their original order within each folder.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. In some cases, publications have had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages scanned. Negatives and slides of artwork have not been scanned.
  - Articles, circa 1910-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Articles, 1914-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Articles, 1920-1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1923-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1927-1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1929-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1931-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Articles, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1937-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Articles, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Articles, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Articles, 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Articles, 1947-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Articles, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Articles, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Articles, 1954-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Articles, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Articles, 1963-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Articles, Encyclopedia of World Art, circa 1956-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Articles, Encyclopedia of World Art, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Articles, Encyclopedia of World Art, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Articles, Encyclopedia of World Art, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Articles, Encyclopedia of World Art, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Articles, Encyclopedia of World Art, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Articles, Encyclopedia of World Art, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Articles, Encyclopedia of World Art, 1963-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Booklets, 1930-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Book, Art Collecting in the United States (research), 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Book, Art Collecting in the United States (research), 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Book, Art Collecting in the United States (research), 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Book, Art Collecting in the United States (research), 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Book, Art Collecting in the United States (notes, #1), 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Book, Art Collecting in the United States (notes, #2), 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Book, Art Collecting in the United States (notes, #3), 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Book, Art Collecting in the United States (notes, #4), 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Book, Art History and Connoisseurship, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Book, Painter's Workshop (correspondence), 1947-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Book, Painter's Workshop (printer's draft), 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Book, Painter's Workshop (clippings), 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Book, Painter's Workshop (research, artists), 1947-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Book, Painter's Workshop (research, artist workshops), 1947-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Book, Painter's Workshop (research, materials), 1947-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Book, Painter's Workshop (research, materials), 1947-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Book, Painter's Workshop (research, techniques), 1947-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Handbook on the Preservation of Paintings (correspondence), 1933-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Handbook on the Preservation of Paintings (International Conference), 1930-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Handbook on the Preservation of Paintings (International Conference), 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Handbook on the Preservation of Paintings (final draft), 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Handbook on the Preservation of Paintings (drafts), 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Translation, "Relations with the German Art Group", circa 1905-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Translation, "The Problem of England", circa 1905-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Unpublished Essay, "Present Economic and Political Forces", 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Unpublished Essay, "Present Economic and Political Forces", 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)